<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Danyal Zia</title>
 <link href="http://danyalzia.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://danyalzia.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-02-28T22:28:28+05:00</updated>
 <id>http://danyalzia.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Danyal Zia</name>
   <email>contact@danyalzia.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Namecheap vs GoDaddy - Why I chose Namecheap over GoDaddy for domain registration</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/28/namecheap-vs-godaddy/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-28T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/28/namecheap-vs-godaddy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://31.media.tumblr.com/be57217c58addd5db3027a9ada849c7a/tumblr_inline_nj03ceP40a1t1et1i.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Namecheap&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;This is my honest piece of review on the services of &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/ref/namecheap&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.godaddy.com/&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;. I only recommend product I personally use.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I created my blog on Tumblr, I badly wanted to buy the custom domain for it. I didn&amp;#39;t want to buy the hosting, as Tumblr already provided the platform for me to blog regularly and create pages for my services. Also, Tubmlr provides almost complete control / customization (HTML/CSS, etc.), so there was no reason for me to buy the hosting for other blogging platforms (self-hosted WordPress, etc.) because I didn&amp;#39;t want that extra functionality of those, such as plugins (i.e., PHP support), etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I did google &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Cheap domains&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; and found GoDaddy on top of the search page, so I thought that they were the most popular domain registrar in the world. I went through the site and completed the signup there, hoping to buy the domain. They register country specific &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-level_domain&quot;&gt;TLD&lt;/a&gt; (Top-Level Domain) as well (&lt;strong&gt;.pk&lt;/strong&gt; in my case), and they were showing the prices in &lt;strong&gt;PKR&lt;/strong&gt;... which seemed good to me, because it had given me the impression that Pakistani entrepreneurs / freelancers prefer to buy domain from them. They were charging around &lt;strong&gt;$14.99 / year *&lt;em&gt;for *&lt;/em&gt;.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain, however, they were forcing me to buy the hosting from them as well, so for me their ordering step wasn&amp;#39;t very user-friendly at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then found another domain registrar, namely, &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/ref/namecheap&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; from the Wikipedia page of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_Daddy&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt; while reading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&quot;&gt;internet freedom controversy&lt;/a&gt;. I visited the page and fell in love with its simplicity. They were giving &lt;strong&gt;.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain for &lt;strong&gt;$10.69 / year&lt;/strong&gt; with a free &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whois&quot;&gt;WHOIS&lt;/a&gt; guard for the first year, so they were indeed cheaper than GoDaddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have any experience in buying the hosting from either of them, but for getting a custom domain for your Tumblr / Blogger / WordPress blog, I would highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/ref/namecheap&quot;&gt;Namcheap&lt;/a&gt; because of their user-friendly website and (a bit) cheaper domain registration.
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Some of the links in this post are “affiliate links.” This means if you click on the link and purchase the item, I will receive an affiliate commission (at no additional cost to you), which is a nice way to support me. Regardless, I only recommend products or services I use personally and believe will add value to my readers. I am disclosing this in accordance with the Federal Trade Commission’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.access.gpo.gov/nara/cfr/waisidx_03/16cfr255_03.html&quot;&gt;16 CFR, Part 255&lt;/a&gt;: “Guides Concerning the Use of Endorsements and Testimonials in Advertising.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>6 Tips For Writing A Killer Cover Letter</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/27/6-tips-for-writing-a-killer-cover-letter/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-27T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/27/6-tips-for-writing-a-killer-cover-letter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;table align=&quot;center&quot; cellpadding=&quot;0&quot; cellspacing=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;tr-caption-container&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;6 tips for writing a killer cover letter&quot; src=&quot;https://31.media.tumblr.com/c1dfb6d6326df80b3306695185ced0da/tumblr_inline_njf70mXStz1t1et1i.jpg&quot; style=&quot;margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;tr-caption&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;(Courtesy: Red Star Resume)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Tired of getting&amp;nbsp;declination of jobs because of poorly written cover letters?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Most of us who are looking for potential jobs in a marketplace need to regularly write cover letters to sell ourselves in a such way that make us stand out of the rest, especially for online work platforms or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freelance_marketplace&quot;&gt;freelance marketplace&lt;/a&gt;. Badly written cover letters give impression to the client that the candidate is a cut/copy paster, that way a client can lose a candidate with the highest potential!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tradition of writing cover letters to clients for making contracts dates back to the days when people started using the medium of written communication to express the formal message.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Having been experienced in writing cover letters to clients while working as a freelance software developer, and getting hired and rejected, I have found 6 crucial things that need to be kept in mind when writing a cover letter. Even though I can't guarantee that the following tips will land you a job, I can say for sure that if you precisely follow these tips, then there is a good chance that the client would enjoy reading your cover letter.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;1) Be specific&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Always highlight your strong points and be specific as to why the client should choose you instead of others of the same set of skills as yours applying for the same job. Do not use general sentences such as, &quot;&lt;b&gt;I'm excellent in HTML/CSS&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, etc., but rather use specific sentences such as, &quot;&lt;b&gt;I feel like I'm very good in HTML/CSS because I have designed ___ site from scratch&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2) Do not copy from previous cover letters&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You can use the previous letter as the basis for your new cover letter, but never copy/paste the exact text from them! The clients would clearly find out that you simply copy-pasted the cover letter and won't take your application seriously as it gives the impression that you didn't pay enough attention to the job requirements.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;3) Never beg for the job&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Never ever beg for the job; it sends a negative impression of yours to the client that you don't have enough skills to do the job. Usage of the word &quot;&lt;b&gt;please&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, particularly in the sentences like &quot;&lt;b&gt;Please hire me&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, &quot;&lt;b&gt;Please do me a favor&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, etc. is highly discouraged! Everyone gets a strong case, you aren't the exception! Use sentences like, &quot;&lt;b&gt;You may need to try me before rejecting my application&lt;/b&gt;&quot; or &quot;&lt;b&gt;You can test my skills before rejecting me for mere lack of experience&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;4) Be personal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You can be personal without begging for the job; that is, you can make a case that you are the only person who is perfect for the job. For instance, suppose a client has posted a job wanting a writer with software development knowledge, then you can tell why you are the only person who is perfect for the job, because you have both writing and software development skills.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;5) Use proper English&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Always use proper English with correct structure, and without any grammatical mistakes, especially for the jobs on content / blog writing, the use of proper English is must. For the non-native writers, I would highly recommend Michael Swan's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0194420981/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0194420981&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=danzia-20&amp;amp;linkId=PXXK2JV4DHOYQOIV&quot;&gt;Practical English Usage&lt;/a&gt;. Any grammatical error in a cover letter can be a break dealer, so it can be a worth investment!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;6) Do not oversell yourself&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Avoid the use of words like &quot;&lt;b&gt;expert&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, &quot;&lt;b&gt;perfect&lt;/b&gt;&quot;, etc. when describing your skills to the clients. Most clients prefer honest individuals who self-assess themselves honestly. Prefer the use of &quot;&lt;b&gt;very good&lt;/b&gt;&quot; or &quot;&lt;b&gt;quite experienced&lt;/b&gt;&quot; instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Know any other tips for writing a killer cover letter that has helped you landing a job? Tell me in the comments section below!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hi, there!</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/25/hi-there/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-25T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/25/hi-there</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have moved my blog / site from Tumblr to Github pages which is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I took this decision because of the slow load time speed of Tumblr, and the fact that Tumblr doesn&amp;#39;t support pretty permalinks. Blog posts that were hosted on Tumblr are successfully imported here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(This section has been improved and then added to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; section of the blog)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
