<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Danyal Zia</title>
 <link href="http://danyalzia.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://danyalzia.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-03-07T00:44:04+05:00</updated>
 <id>http://danyalzia.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Danyal Zia</name>
   <email>contact@danyalzia.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Remember us, for we too have lived, loved, and laughed</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/03/07/remember-us-for-we-too-have-lived-loved-and-laughed/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-07T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/03/07/remember-us-for-we-too-have-lived-loved-and-laughed</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a short Facebook note on my thoughts about this fascinating quote in the movie &amp;quot;Shutter Island&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;fb-root&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script&gt;(function(d, s, id) {  var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];  if (d.getElementById(id)) return;  js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;  js.src = &quot;//connect.facebook.net/en_US/all.js#xfbml=1&quot;;  fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);}(document, 'script', 'facebook-jssdk'));&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fb-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/danyal-zia/remember-us-for-we-too-have-lived-loved-and-laughed/1012355488778554&quot; data-width=&quot;466&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;fb-xfbml-parse-ignore&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/notes/danyal-zia/remember-us-for-we-too-have-lived-loved-and-laughed/1012355488778554&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/danyal.zia.k&quot;&gt;Danyal Zia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Site migrated from Tumblr to Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/03/01/migrated-to-jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/03/01/migrated-to-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have moved my blog / site from Tumblr to Github pages which is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I took this decision because of the slow load time speed of Tumblr, and the fact that Tumblr doesn&amp;#39;t support pretty permalinks. Blog posts that were hosted on Tumblr are successfully imported here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Namecheap vs GoDaddy - Why I chose Namecheap over GoDaddy for domain registration</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/28/namecheap-vs-godaddy/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-28T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/28/namecheap-vs-godaddy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../media/images/namecheap-vs-godaddy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Namecheap vs GoDaddy&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;This is my honest piece of review on the services of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=77601&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.godaddy.com/&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt;. I only recommend product I personally use.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I created my personal homepage / blog on Tumblr (it was before I moved it to Jekyll), I badly wanted to buy the custom domain for it. I didn&amp;#39;t want to buy the hosting, as Tumblr already provided the platform for me to blog regularly and create pages for my services and contact information. Also, Tubmlr provided almost complete control / customization (HTML/CSS, etc.), so there was no reason for me to buy the hosting for other blogging platforms (self-hosted WordPress, etc.) because I didn&amp;#39;t want that extra functionality of those, such as plugins (i.e., PHP support), etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I did google &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Cheap domains&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; and found GoDaddy on top of the search page, so I thought that they were the most popular domain registrar in the world. I went through the site and completed the signup there, hoping to buy the domain. They register country specific &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top-level_domain&quot;&gt;TLD&lt;/a&gt; (Top-Level Domain) as well (&lt;strong&gt;.pk&lt;/strong&gt; in my case), and they were showing the prices in &lt;strong&gt;PKR&lt;/strong&gt;... which seemed good to me, because that had given me the impression that Pakistani entrepreneurs / freelancers prefer to buy domain from them. They were charging around &lt;strong&gt;$14.99 / year *&lt;em&gt;for *&lt;/em&gt;.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain, however, they were forcing me to buy the hosting from them as well, so for me their ordering step wasn&amp;#39;t very user-friendly at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then found another domain registrar, namely, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=77601&quot;&gt;Namecheap&lt;/a&gt; from the Wikipedia page of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go_Daddy&quot;&gt;GoDaddy&lt;/a&gt; while reading the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stop_Online_Piracy_Act&quot;&gt;internet freedom controversy&lt;/a&gt;. I visited the page and fell in love with its simplicity. They were giving &lt;strong&gt;.com&lt;/strong&gt; domain for &lt;strong&gt;$10.69 / year&lt;/strong&gt; with a free &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whois&quot;&gt;WHOIS&lt;/a&gt; guard for the first year, so they were indeed cheaper than GoDaddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have any experience in buying the hosting from either of them, but for getting a custom domain for your blog, I would highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/?aff=77601&quot;&gt;Namcheap&lt;/a&gt; because of their user-friendly website and (a bit) cheaper domain registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Some of the links above are affiliate links)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>6 Tips For Writing A Killer Cover Letter</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/27/6-tips-for-writing-a-killer-cover-letter/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-27T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/27/6-tips-for-writing-a-killer-cover-letter</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../media/images/6-Tips-For-Writing-A-Killer-Cover-Letter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6 Tips For Writing A Killer Cover Letter&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;url&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy: Red Star Resume&quot;&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tired of getting declination of jobs because of poorly written cover letters?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us who are looking for potential jobs in a marketplace need to regularly write cover letters to sell ourselves in a such way that make us stand out of the rest, especially for online work platforms or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freelance_marketplace&quot;&gt;freelance marketplace&lt;/a&gt;. Badly written cover letters give impression to the client that the candidate is a cut / copy paster, that way a client can lose a candidate with the highest potential!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tradition of writing cover letters to clients for making contracts dates back to the days when people started using the medium of written communication to express the formal message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been experienced in writing cover letters to clients while working as a freelance software developer, and getting hired and rejected, I have found 6 crucial things that need to be kept in mind when writing a cover letter. Even though I can&amp;#39;t guarantee that the following tips will land you a job, I can say for sure that if you precisely follow these tips, then there is a good chance that the client would enjoy reading your cover letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1) Be specific&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always highlight your strong points and be specific as to why the client should choose you instead of others of the same set of skills as yours applying for the same job. Do not use general sentences such as, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;#39;m excellent in HTML/CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, etc., but rather use specific sentences such as, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;I feel like I&amp;#39;m very good in HTML/CSS because I have designed ___ site from scratch&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2) Do not copy from previous cover letters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the previous letter as the basis for your new cover letter, but never copy / paste the exact text from them! The clients would clearly find out that you simply copy-pasted the cover letter and won&amp;#39;t take your application seriously as it gives the impression that you didn&amp;#39;t pay enough attention to the job requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3) Never beg for the job&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never ever beg for the job; it sends a negative impression of yours to the client that you don&amp;#39;t have enough skills to do the job. Usage of the word &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;please&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, particularly in the sentences like &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Please hire me&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Please do me a favor&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, etc. is highly discouraged! Everyone gets a strong case, you aren&amp;#39;t the exception! Use sentences like, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;You may need to try me before rejecting my application&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;You can test my skills before rejecting me for mere lack of experience&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4) Be personal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can be personal without begging for the job; that is, you can make a case that you are the only person who is perfect for the job. For instance, suppose a client has posted a job wanting a writer with software development knowledge, then you can tell why you are the only person who is perfect for the job, because you have both writing and software development skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5) Use proper English&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always use proper English with correct structure, and without any grammatical mistakes, especially for the jobs on content / blog writing, the use of proper English is must. For the non-native writers, I would highly recommend Michael Swan&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0194420981/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;amp;creativeASIN=0194420981&amp;amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;amp;tag=danzia-20&amp;amp;amp;linkId=PXXK2JV4DHOYQOIV&quot;&gt;Practical English Usage&lt;/a&gt;. Any grammatical error in a cover letter can be a break dealer, so it can be a worth investment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;6) Do not oversell yourself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid the use of words like &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;expert&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;perfect&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot;, etc. when describing your skills to the clients. Most clients prefer honest individuals who self-assess themselves honestly. Prefer the use of &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;very good&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;quite experienced&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know any other tips for writing a killer cover letter that has helped you landing a job? Tell me in the comments section below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Programming blog posts have been migrated to my sister-site</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/18/programming-blog-migrated/"/>
   <updated>2015-02-18T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/02/18/programming-blog-migrated</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-G-TPx3yzWFU/VO-QV1nGTTI/AAAAAAAAAMQ/iGyzkk-opcA/s1600/CMYH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coding Makes You Happy!&quot;&gt;
I have migrated the programming posts / guides that were hosted on this blog to my sister-site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://codingmakesyouhappy.com&quot;&gt;Coding Makes You Happy!&lt;/a&gt;. From now on, this blog is about my opinions on programming, software development and personal development, so all the future programming tutorials will reside in the aforementioned site.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Created a separate blog for programming tutorials</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/28/separate-programming-blog/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-28T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/28/separate-programming-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another intuitive. This time I have created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://codingmakesyouhappy.com&quot;&gt;separate blog for programming&lt;/a&gt;. The reason for this is that I want this site/blog to be my personal/professional home page only, and I don&amp;#39;t want to fill it with programming tutorials. The tutorials that are hosted on this blog will be migrated to the aforementioned blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Now you can subscribe to my mailing list</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/16/subscribe-to-mailing-list/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-16T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/16/subscribe-to-mailing-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added the newsletter sign-up form to my programming blog, which is powered by MailChimp. Through it, you can get the tips on programming/coding and emails which is driven by RSS-email campaign. Feel free to subscribe, I won&amp;#39;t spam you, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Fiverr Gig on blog writing on programming topics</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/15/my-fiverr-gig/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-15T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/15/my-fiverr-gig</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a created a Gig on programming in &lt;a href=&quot;http://fiverr.com/danyalzia&quot;&gt;Fiverr&lt;/a&gt; about 2 months ago, but unfortunately, it didn&amp;#39;t sell very well. Now, I have improved the information on it with proper images. Feel free to buy Gigs through it if you want me to write a programming blog / article for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pinterest account created</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/10/pinterest-account-created/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-10T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/10/pinterest-account-created</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I created my account on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pinterest.com/danyalzia&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt;, which is a visual discovery tool. Through it, one can create different boards to pin (post) different images. It is a great way to keep yourself reminded of the message in the images, such as, New Year resolutions, motivational quotes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Religious dogmatism and conviction in a nutshell</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/02/religious-dogmatism-and-conviction/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-02T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/02/religious-dogmatism-and-conviction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/media/images/religious-conviction.png&quot; alt=&quot;Relgious Conviction&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;url&quot; alt=&quot;Relgious Conviction&quot;&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the 21st century and the world has become a global village. People have become civilized, intellectually independent and started questioning their faith; you can’t force your beliefs on others and expect them to give respect to you! Humans have evolved intellectually and realized that organized religions and ideologies only killed more people and deterred progression. If you think that girls shouldn’t be in schools or women without veil don’t deserve respect or people deserves to die for merely holding a different belief and writing a book criticizing your faith, then you have so much in common with the Taliban, ISIS, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans deserve respect, ideologies don’t. Keep your religion to yourself, and your life and others’ life will be great!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hi, there!</title>
   <link href="http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/01/hi-there/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00+05:00</updated>
   <id>http://danyalzia.com/2015/01/01/hi-there</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(This was the first blog post when I created my blog on Tumblr. Many things have changed since then, most prominently the migration of this site from &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/2015/03/01/migrated-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Tumblr to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I have decided to host old posts here as well so that I can see the improvements in my writing style).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the introductory post and my initial expression on Tumblr for a personal site/blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Danyal Zia, I live in Karachi, Pakistan — a fast &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economy_of_Karachi&quot;&gt;developing city&lt;/a&gt;. I’m graduating at University of Karachi, where I’m studying software engineering. I like to program applications, my main interest is in native compiled programming languages. I prefer static/strongly typed languages such as C, C++ and D. In the recent months, I have contributed to some open-source softwares that are hosted on Github. I occasionally host my projects and code snippets there too, at the moment I’m developing the direct bindings of Irrlicht 3D Engine (which is originally written in C++) for D programming language — a language which I admires a lot — for which I will post later. I currently do freelancing in software development and a content writer. Apart from programming and writing skills, I like to play (guitar, keyboards etc) and listen (rock mostly) music. I regularly do cover of contemporary rock songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tumblr — as a CMS seemed very appealing to me. I was seduced by the fact that you can create unlimited sites with it for free and the custom domain can be later brought from domain registrar at a quite reasonable prize. When I began working as a freelancer, I had an ambition to make my personal site — a site which can be one-stop shop on my contact information. So, I decided to try Tumblr for both the CMS and site hosting, and I’m quite happy with it. Once I get enough recognition, I will buy the custom domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Feel free to poke around the site and &lt;a href=&quot;http://danyalzia.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if needed!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
